[
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question": "How can we access private method of a class from outside the class?",
    "answer": "We can use Reflection to access private method of a class from outside the class. IN Java, we use getDeclaredMethod() to get instance of a private method. Then we mark this method accessible and finally invoke it. In following sample code, we are accessing private method message() of class Foo by Reflection. FileName: Foo.java public class Foo { private void message(){System.out.println(\"hello java\"); } } FileName: FooMethodCall.java import java.lang.reflect.Method; public class FooMethodCall{ public static void main(String[] args)throws Exception{ Class c = Class.forName(\"Foo\"); Object o= c.newInstance(); Method m =c.getDeclaredMethod(\"message\", null); m.setAccessible(true); m.invoke(o, null); } }",
    "topic": "OOP Concepts",
    "tags": [
      "oop concepts",
      "java"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "question": "Why do we use Static Nested interface in Java?",
    "answer": "Only the enclosing class can access a Static Nested interface. Consider following code in which interface Xyz is enclosed in class Abc. public class Abc { public interface Xyz { void callback(); } public static void registerCallback(Xyz xyz) {...} } // Client Code Abc.registerCallback(new Abc.Xyz() { public void callback() {...} }); Any code that cannot access Abc can not access interface Xyz also. So the purpose of declaring an Inner interface is to restrict its access from outside world. String",
    "topic": "Java Basics",
    "tags": [
      "java basics",
      "java"
    ]
  }
]
